There are several situations where you should always call 911 immediately.
This includes if someone is unresponsive, experiencing chest discomfort, or showing
signs of a stroke.
You should also call for severe injuries like deep burns or heavy bleeding, seizures, electric
shocks, or if someone has been exposed to poison.
Anytime there is a problem with breathing, a suspected head, neck, or back injury, a
possible broken bone, or complications related to pregnancy, 911 is your first priority.
This also applies if you see blood in someone's stool or vomit.
When you get a dispatcher on the line, be sure to give them your exact location and
answer all of their questions clearly.
Don't worry about the questions slowing things down.
Answering them actually helps help get to you faster.
Try to put your phone on speaker so you can keep your hands free to provide care while
following the dispatcher's instructions.
It is a great idea to memorize the addresses of places you visit often, like your office
or a gym, so you can give that information instantly during an emergency.